Mandeep Singh

Startups Developer, Laravel Expert, Full Stack Developer, Freelance Architect & Consultant New Delhi

9999340849

mSingh.me

in linkedin.com/in/meSingh9

github.com/meSingh

Summary

From last 7+ years, I've mostly worked on Laravel Framework based Projects in combination with many other technologies like AngularJS, VueJS, MongoDB, a bit of Python and almost all other sorts of languages. The kind of projects I've done has grown my skills so much that languages don't matter to me anymore & I can work on anything.

Work Experience

Founder & Lead Developer

Dec 2015 - Present

Khurafat

Khurafat is just a gang of some crazy developers who devote their free time to make useful tools and products for the open source community and give something back to the community.

Technologies Used:

- * Laravel Framework
- * VueJS Framework
- * Symphany Components
- * Elastic Search

Principal Software Architect - Consultant

Jul 2017 - Present

Fourtek IT Solutions Pvt. Ltd.

Founder & Lead Developer

Apr 2015 - Present

Laratisans

Laravel Artisans: building laravel packages & open source tools for & with Laravel. Get help or help us make something awesome for Laravel Community.

Technologies Used:

- * Laravel Framework
- * VuelS Framework
- * Symphany Components
- * Jekyll

Acting CTO - HumanFirewall

Dec 2016 - Aug 2017

Lloyds Ventures

Lloyds Ventures is a multinational investment company with investments in Telecom, Media & Cyber Security across Europe, Middle East & Asia. The team brings along vast industry knowledge and has partnered to incubate path breaking innovations in their respective fields.

Lead Software Engineer

Nov 2016 - May 2017

LetsMD

LetsMD.com is an Online Healthcare Services Portal to compare costs of various treatments at various Centres in India.

Technologies Used:

- * Laravel Framework
- * Angular JS
- * Node JS
- * Gulp, Automated Build System
- * Swagger Specifications

Services Used:

- * AWS RDS
- * AWS S3
- * AWS SES
- * Google Places

Senior Development Consultant

Jun 2016 - Oct 2016

BioHiring India Pvt. Ltd.

Created the core architecture of complete product i.e. Frontend & Backend alongside continues assistance for the development of platforms version 2. Also, helped in hiring more telent and supervision of technical team.

Technologies Used:

- * Laravel Framework
- * Angular JS
- * Node JS
- * Gulp, Automated Build System
- * Swagger Specifications

Services Used:

- * AWS RDS
- * AWS S3
- * AWS SES
- * Google Places

Seinor Consultant Architect

Jun 2016 - Oct 2016

CST Infotech Pvt. Ltd.

Lead a team to develop a modular, pluggable social platform for a reputed newspaper website.

Technologies Used:

- * Laravel Framework
- * MongoDB
- * Elastic Search

Senior Backend Consultant

Jun 2016 - Oct 2016

SuperLorry Services Pvt. Ltd.

Helped develop the initial version of the platform along with rest of the team. Also assisted in setting up development standards & architecture for future developments.

Technologies Used:

- * Laravel Framework
- * OAuth 2 Implementation
- * Angular JS
- * Vagrant

Consultant Technical Architect - ShipRocket

ShipRocket - KartRocket

Created the core architecture & Lead a team of 5 for a new products development which no one else was able to make. Researched the market, met clients & created the core version without much help or guidance.

Technologies Used:

- * Laravel Framework
- * Queues & Beandtalkd
- * Command Line Interfaces & Scheduled Tasks
- * Angular IS
- * Gulp: Automated Build System
- * LESS

Founder & Lead PHP Developer

Nov 2012 - Jul 2015

WebsterFolks

WebsterFolks.com is a developement agency specialised in Laravel based projects. It has helped over 400 clients so far to help build their startups or websites.

Development Lead

Dec 2015 - Feb 2016

TheSmartTrolley.com

The Smart Trolley is a modern hyper local e-grocery platform to cater to Delhi & NCR. Right from your everyday staples like dals, cereals and flour, to health food, to cakes and bake – if there's any household product or equipment that you have on your mind, you'll find it at The Smart Trolley.com.

Senior Web Developer

Jun 2015 - Aug 2015

BetterButter.in

BetterButter is the most fun and personal way to discover recipes in India!....

Freelance Web Developer

Mar 2013 - Present

Envato Stuio

Envato Studio is a community of hand-picked designers, developers and digital talent, available to work on your project. From logo design to web development, to video production, we make it easy to connect and work together to get your job done.

Freelace WordPress Specialist

Aug 2012 - Jun 2015

Elto.com

Elto.com is a curated marketplace of developers and marketers helping small business grow online.

Elto got Acquired by GoDaddy in 2015 and is now known as Godaddy Pro Marketplace.

Freelance Web Developer

May 2012 - Jun 2014

Envato Market

Envato Market is home to thousands of talented designers, developers and creators of all kinds, who sell a huge range of digital goods and assets. There's everything from photographs to project files, sound effects to video templates.

Freelance Web Developer

Mar 2012 - Dec 2012

Fiverr.com

The marketplace for creative & professional services

Have been doing freelance development for several years for local as well as international clients.

Skills

Project Management			
Laravel PHP Framework			
Team Managment			
Lumen PHP Framework			
Database Designing			
Codeigniter PHP Framework			
RESTful API's			
Amazon Web Services			
VueJS			
PHP			
NodeJS			
AngularJS			
Python			

Education

Bachelor of Business Administration (BBA Currently Pursuing) Sikkim Manipal University - Distance Education	2015 - 2018
Senior School (Class 11 & 12) Shri Guru Harkishan Sen Sec School	2005 - 2007
High School (Class 10) Daffodil Public High School	1994 - 2005